<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>news | RCODI</title>
    <link>/tag/news/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>news</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Purdue Research Center for Open Digital Innovation © 2022</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/media/logo_hue831a1547d228cf33d75a995b069998a_11256_300x300_fit_lanczos_2.png</url>
      <title>news</title>
      <link>/tag/news/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Brunswicker to panel about bridging art and science</title>
      <link>/post/innovation-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/innovation-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;icis-panel-bridging-art-and-science-in-digital-innovation-transformation-and-entrepreneurship&#34;&gt;ICIS Panel: Bridging Art and Science in Digital Innovation, Transformation, and Entrepreneurship&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Brunswicker will be paneling at the 2021 ICIS on the synergy between art and science in digital innovation, transformation, and enterepreneurship (DITE). Joined by five additional scholars, Dr. Brunswicker cover topics relevant to the bridge of art and sciences in theorizing, discussing art-science theorizing within the DITE environment, and talk about how research centers can impact the research progres on this novel yet largely unexplored phenomenon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New EdSurge Podcast Series Features RCODI Director</title>
      <link>/post/6600-new-edsurge-podcast-series-features-rcodi-director/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2020 01:39:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/6600-new-edsurge-podcast-series-features-rcodi-director/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a new podcast series from EdSurge, RCODI Director, Professor Sabine Brunswicker, shares her experience teaching at the Purdue Polytechnic Institute during the Fall 2020 semester amidst the ongoing COVID-19 pandemic. Along with other professors from around the country, including Purdue&amp;rsquo;s Dr. Deborah Nichols, Associate Professor of Human Development and Family Studies, and Purdue student Joseph Ching, these individuals are creating digital diaries of their experiences on campus. Find out what the educational experience is like from their perspective in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.edsurge.com/research/guides/pandemic-campus-diaries-a-podcast-series&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;first episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.edsurge.com/research/guides/pandemic-campus-diaries-a-podcast-series?fbclid=IwAR2rMUdCD0HfyUKMnfdcSsd96xFMuJPVOr4Sr57U8HUR-mjTvyLu46QcvG4&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RCODI’s Director Co-organizing a Virtual LIVE workshop on Digital Transformation at AOM</title>
      <link>/post/6595-rcodis-director-co-organizing-a-virtual-live-workshop-on-digital-transformation-at-aom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 01:16:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/6595-rcodis-director-co-organizing-a-virtual-live-workshop-on-digital-transformation-at-aom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our director is participating on the 80th annual meeting of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://aom.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Academy of Management&lt;/a&gt;.   What’s new is that this year the meeting is virtual. She will be a co-organizer of a LIVE Professional Development Workshop “What’s New About Digital Transformation? Exploring Interdisciplinary, Multi-Level Research Ideas,” along with five other experts from Switzerland, Italy, Denmark and Germany.  More than 250 have signed up to participate in the virtual workshop so we are eager how this virtual experience on a timely topic will play out!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thought Leadership and Digital Innovation in Times of Crisis</title>
      <link>/post/6576-thought-leadership-and-digital-innovation-in-times-of-crisis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 02:23:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/6576-thought-leadership-and-digital-innovation-in-times-of-crisis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;RCODI Director Sabine Brunswicker recently gave a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ispim-innovation.com/post/sabine-brunswicker-on-responding-to-the-crisis-with-digital-innovation&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;keynote talk&lt;/a&gt; as part of ISPIM’s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ispim-virtual.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;virtual conference&lt;/a&gt; on responding to the COVID-19 crisis. The virtual conference was held June 7-10, 2020 with many leading researchers and experts in the interdisciplinary fields of innovation. As a top thought leader in this area, she discussed her passion for researching about digital platforms, and the interplay between AI and human intelligence. During the talk, Professor Brunswicker shared details on how crowds can help in responding to this type of complex epidemiological and economic crisis through digital innovation. In particular, digital innovation via crowds can help reduce levels of uncertainty while also focusing attention on flexibility, diversity of ideas, sustainability and resource efficiency. Additionally, Professor Brunswicker highlights how crises can create certain unexpected events and changes which make traditional AI models fragile, thus benefiting from the human intelligence component.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The original talk was presented on June 9th, 2020, but recordings are available from ISPIM through July 15th, 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research on a &#34;Theory of Design Motifs&#34;</title>
      <link>/post/6552-research-on-a-theory-of-design-motifs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 14:16:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/6552-research-on-a-theory-of-design-motifs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our Director Sabine Brunswicker and RCODI fellow Satyam Mukherjee have been &lt;a href=&#34;https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=3568249&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;working on a paper&lt;/a&gt; that proposes a theory of design network motifs and conducts an empirical examination of this phenomena utilizing data from the Open Stack repository NOVA. The results of the study contribute to existing literature on design architecture as well as open collaboration by offering an explanation of hidden dependencies within a complex system architecture.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RCODI Director to Present Virtual Keynote at ISPIM Conference</title>
      <link>/post/6546-rcodi-director-to-present-virtual-keynote-at-ispim-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 20:12:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/6546-rcodi-director-to-present-virtual-keynote-at-ispim-conference/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;RCODI Director Sabine Brunswicker is scheduled to present a keynote talk on open digital innovation at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ispim-virtual.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ISPIM Virtual Conference&lt;/a&gt; being hosted June 7-10, 2020. The role of digital technologies, AI and distributed innovation to resolve societal challenges is especially critical at this time and Prof. Brunswicker will share insights from her research and experience as they relate to the conference theme of “Innovating in Times of Crisis.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to our new PhD student at RCODI</title>
      <link>/post/6532-welcome-to-our-new-phd-student-at-rcodi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 18:36:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/6532-welcome-to-our-new-phd-student-at-rcodi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In May 2020, Jia Cheoh was accepted as PhD student of Professor Sabine Brunswicker. Jia will be graduating this semester with a Bachelor’s degree from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cs.purdue.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Department of Computer Science&lt;/a&gt; with a focus in software engineering and notes, “I am excited to get started with this new journey!” She has been supporting the research efforts of Professor Brunswicker over the last few years including the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ironhacks.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;IronHacks&lt;/a&gt; project. Along with her work at RCODI, Jia has experience with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rcac.purdue.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Purdue Supercomputing Center&lt;/a&gt;, Google, and various startups including her own company.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PLOS ONE Call for Papers: Cities as Complex Systems</title>
      <link>/post/6536-plos-one-call-for-papers-cities-as-complex-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 19:25:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/6536-plos-one-call-for-papers-cities-as-complex-systems/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cities are centers of human interactions and the innovations that arise from them. Urbanization has led to many positive developments for society, but also contributes to many of our most pressing challenges, from sustainability and climate change to poverty and inequality. Concepts from complex systems and network theory provide valuable approaches to further our understanding of the processes which drive how cities form, grow, and operate as environments which are more than the sum of their parts. With its commitment to open access, and rigorous, reproducible research,&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://journals.plos.org/plosone/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;is the ideal venue for interdisciplinary complexity science.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Our director, an academic editor of PLOS ONE in the area of network science/complex systems is excited to announce a Call for Papers on Cities as Complex Systems, bringing together researchers across scientific disciplines to build a collection of complex systems and networks research applied to questions in urban science. Our Guest Editors Marta González and Diego Rybski are particularly interested in reading research on urban mobility and energy infrastructures, the morphology and efficiency of cities, and applications to sustainable development goals.&lt;em&gt;Topics may include but are not limited to urban mobility and migration, urban scaling laws, social networks within cities, urban resilience, financial networks within and between cities, smart cities and internet-of-things, and agent-based models of urban phenomena. More details can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://collections.plos.org/s/cities&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;here&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. The submission deadline is July 3, 2020.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding collaboration in open source platforms</title>
      <link>/post/5816-open-source/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2018 00:51:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/5816-open-source/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://rcodi.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/11_3-2X1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt; Everything in life can be connected to a pattern. Whether it be in the way the golden ratio is correlated with growth in shells or how the Pythagorean model is the reason we have stable structures, nature will always hold the key to predicting our own behavior and understanding more about ourselves. It is with this idea that &lt;a href=&#34;https://rcodi.org/ourpeople&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Dr. Sabine Brunswicker and Dr. Satyam Mukherjee&lt;/a&gt; set off to model dynamics between others in design and collaboration. Using the concept of &lt;a href=&#34;https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=313965&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;motif structures&lt;/a&gt;, something typically used for describing and organizing href=&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://science.sciencemag.org/content/298/5594/824%3Ebiological&#34;&gt;http://science.sciencemag.org/content/298/5594/824&amp;gt;biological&lt;/a&gt; systems, the two analyzed how files are linked instead, gaining insight into the collaborative design of source code. left no-repeat;center top;; When reprogramming and re-purposing a certain design part through modifying source files, each individual splits, augments, and inverts which change design interdependence among a small set of files. With this research, we will be able to understand the micro-level design actions that underpin the evolution of a large design artifact developed in fluid organizational forms like open source collaboration. In there, individuals self-select into tasks and make design decisions using simple heuristics (rather than real-option informed design choices). left no-repeat;center top;; Dr. Mukherjee presented their work at the Indian Institute of Management Ahmadabad this month at the international conference on &lt;a href=&#34;http://science.sciencemag.org/content/298/5594/824&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Network Science in Economics and Finance. &lt;/a&gt; left no-repeat;center top;;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nudging people in good behavior with data: the opportunity of “white” design patterns in social data visualizations</title>
      <link>/post/5665-nudging/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 20:30:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/5665-nudging/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://rcodi.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Capture.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt; An accidental subscription to an unwanted newsletter. Extra items in your cart your never added. The seemingly impossible task of deactivating your account on a service you no longer use. All of the above are examples of dark design patterns, or “dark UX,” where the design of a website or application is meant to benefit the brand rather than the user—even at the expense of the latter. Dark design patterns are actually a type of digital nudging, creating user-interface in a way that influences the audience’s choices. While being subconsciously influenced by what we use seems frightening, what if we could influence people to do good? left no-repeat;center top;; &lt;img src=&#34;https://rcodi.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DpjjZFKX4AE5NQG.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt; That is one of the core ideas to Dr. Sabine Brunswicker and Marlen Promann’s research in The Effect of Proximity in Social Data Charts on Perceived Utility. Brunswicker and Promann discuss findings on the dissonance between visual structure and statistical structure, and how its misuse tends to result in misinterpretations. However, when used correctly, visual elements such as charts can actually elicit responses of unity and overcome certain problems such as social loafing—when certain members in a group get benefits from the group’s accomplishments despite not actively contributing like the other members. With this effect, people could be prompted to care more for larger issues that most of us tend to ignore such as sustainability. left no-repeat;center top;; 289787716 700 400 This research has opened the way for future projects on what could be called “white UX”, or design that influences its consumers to become more selfless. Through their work on visual elements and how charts can promote unity among its viewers, they have discovered a new possibility to potentially solving macro-scale social issues. left no-repeat;center top;; If you are interested in learning more, check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oyfW1kkSsGg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt; showing a practical application of data visualization, developed as part of the broader NSF grant this research is connected, or &lt;a href=&#34;http://ieeevis.org/year/2018/info/papers&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt; to the IEEE Information Visualization Conference where this work was presented. left no-repeat;center top;;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IronHacks Fellowship Fall 2018</title>
      <link>/post/5554-fellowship2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 21:05:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/5554-fellowship2019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://rcodi.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/CODE-2X1.jpg&#34;&gt;https://rcodi.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/CODE-2X1.jpg&lt;/a&gt; center &lt;img src=&#34;https://rcodi.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/Logo_1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://rcodi.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/Logo_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;rcodi-fellowship-fall-2018&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RCODI Fellowship Fall 2018&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-should-i-become-an-rcodi-undergraduate-fellow-for-fall-2018&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why should I become an RCODI undergraduate fellow for Fall 2018?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our state has a serious workforce problem. There more than 200,000 unfilled jobs and many counties are not taking the right measures to develop the skills of their residents. Do you want to make a change to our state’s workforce problem using data visualization? Become an undergraduate RCODI fellow for Fall 2018 (with a guaranteed stipend for the first 8 weeks) and join a cohort of other 30 to 50 students who want to use their creativity, technical skills, and analytical mind to make an impact on governments!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please review the following steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read the information about the fellowship below.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complete the registration form that is at the end of this page or direct link &lt;a href=&#34;https://rcodi.org/fellowship-registration-form/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;apply-here-httpsrcodiorgfellowship-registration-form&#34;&gt;Apply &lt;a href=&#34;https://rcodi.org/fellowship-registration-form/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-is-the-fellowship-structured&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How is the fellowship structured?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Research Center for Open Digital Innovation (RCODI) is collaborating with the Indiana Department of Workforce Development (DWD) to launch a unique data analytics fellowship program focused on the area of &lt;strong&gt;workforce analytics&lt;/strong&gt;. The fellowship is open for a cohort of undergraduate students enrolled at Purdue University (between 30 to 50 students will be admitted) that go through a two-stage program, including undergraduate research, in which they analyze, visualize and interactively display their results in web-based “app” to be used by policymakers for their decisions on workforce development in the state of Indiana.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The full program is structured in two phases. Phase 1 includes the 8-week program, in which undergraduate students explore open governmental data as well as workforce data available for the selected fellows only (e.g. skill-level, unfilled jobs, training opportunities). They will analyze, visualize the data, and make them actionable in an interactive web “app” using technologies like HTML, CSS, and D3.js (see cool data visualizations done in D3.js in Figure 1 below).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://rcodi.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/Figure1_fellowship.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Figure 1: D3.js visualizations (&lt;a href=&#34;https://d3js.org/&#34;&gt;https://d3js.org/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal is to develop an interactive app that is used by the governmental actors and agencies when making important workforce-related decisions. The first phase is set-up as hacking challenge run by RCODI, in which a cohort of 30 to 50 students go through a structured training and tutorial program, and then participate in 5 iterative hacking events, in which they use their creativity to develop novel and useful workforce apps. Depending on performance in the first 8 weeks, Phase 2 includes the opportunity for a longer-term fellowship follow-on for selected top students to deepen their analysis and advance their project further individually or in a small team setting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first phase lasts 8 weeks and is structured in distinct phases visualized in the figure below. It starts with pre-training sessions to familiarize participants with technologies (e.g. APIs, D3.js) needed, followed by a 5-stage iterative on-campus competition. During this training period, you will also be familiarized with the DWD data during sessions run by representatives of the state, and a team of data scientists. Fellows will have access to tutorials, live help sessions, a social coding environment, and community features. Automatic hosting of apps, code evaluations, and workflow support for usability judging provides additional assistance to the hackers in agile design and prototyping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://rcodi.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/Figure2_fellowship.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Figure 2: Process for phase 1 of the hacking program.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The training period will start on October 12-14th. The competition portion of the fellowship will take place over 5 weekends in October and November (see below). Students will develop their apps in our lab setting on weekends: &lt;strong&gt;October 19-21&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;October 26-28&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;November 2-4&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;November 9-11&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;November 16-18&lt;/strong&gt;. Meeting times on weekends will be defined in coordination with fellows!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-can-the-candidate-gain-from-the-fellowship&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What can the candidate gain from the fellowship?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of the program, the candidates that are chosen to participate will receive a stipend, a certificate of participation, direct interaction with our state’s decisionmakers and other thought leaders in addition to a real working product that can be included in the candidate&amp;rsquo;s digital portfolio for future references. This is on top of the financial “base reward” of $100 for 8 weeks. This base stipend is independent of the performance of the participants. The final financial reward is allocated based on the participants standing in the cohort (below lowest 25% of the participants, better than the lower 25% quartile but worse than 50% of the participants, better than 50% of the fellows but worse than the upper 25%, in the upper 25% quartile). The top 25% can receive a final payment of $800 dollars. The reward depends on how well the fellows score at each stage of the competition in the area of analytics, information visualization, and novelty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-happens-during-the-first-phase-of-the-fellowship&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What happens during the first phase of the fellowship?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You will tackle a real-world challenge in the area of workforce analytics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You will prepare and analyze open data as well as ‘restricted’ data that are exclusively available for the fellows through the collaboration with DWD.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You will advance your skills in HTML, CSS, and D3.js during the training session&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You will use analytical thinking and creativity when exploring, correlating, and visualizing the data in order to respond to the hacking challenge presented to you at the start of the hacking challenge.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You will create and test a web-based app that is novel in terms of data visualization (D3.js) and also interactive features. You will also test your prototype in the lab.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You will participate in and experience experimental lab studies using eye-tracking technologies and data science methods (A/B testing).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You will interact with a team of experts (professors, researchers, representatives of DWD, team members of the chief data scientists of Indiana).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You will have the opportunity to present your final outcomes in a presentation to a board of experts consisting of DWD, other policymakers, and Purdue researchers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your final study will be published as a short whitepaper including a demonstration of your prototype.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sounds overwhelming? We will be here to support you: There are tutors, mentors, etc. who will help you in this program to ramp up fast. We will have a training period! There will be also free food on weekends and drinks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;criteria-for-selection-of-candidates&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Criteria for selection of candidates:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The candidate will need to present proof of the following requirements:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enrolled in a program requiring programming experience (computer science, computer graphics technology, engineering or related areas) or other evidence for prior programming experience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evidence with interest on learning and having experience in developing web applications using HTML/CSS/Javascript&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Problem-solving skills and the ability and willingness to learn new techniques quickly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interest in data visualization and data analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ideally also prior experience with Javascript and D3.js, learning and doing cool stuff!!!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-are-the-next-steps-to-become-part-of-the-fellowship-cohort-for-fall-2018&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are the next steps to become part of the fellowship cohort for Fall 2018?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interested students will need to submit an application &lt;a href=&#34;https://rcodi.org/fellowship-registration-form/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once registration is open, submissions are time sensitive! &lt;strong&gt;The application deadline is Sunday, October 7, 2018 at 11:59pm.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also download the complete information &lt;a href=&#34;https://rcodi.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/Fellowship-document.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;about-rcodi&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About RCODI&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Research Center for Open Digital Innovation (RCODI) at Purdue University brings together an interdisciplinary group of scholars and thinkers focused on the emerging phenomenon of open digital innovation. Open digital innovation encompasses completely new ways we create and use information and data-driven products and services. We design and evaluate data-driven applications and smart technologies to tackle societal challenges such as sustainability, safety, healthy living. Social coding platforms and virtual hacking communities serve as our virtual living labs. Our researchers use advance techniques of computational social science such as behavioral analytics and large-scale online experiments to develop new digital technologies that support humans in the role as citizens, workers, and policymakers in making smarter decisions. As user-inspired researchers, we intensively engage with industry partners, policymakers, and individual citizens. In 2016, RCODI launched Purdue IronHacks, a unique virtual multi-staged open data competition, in which students and innovators develop novel and useful apps to solve societal challenges. More Information about RCODI: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rcodi.org&#34;&gt;www.rcodi.org&lt;/a&gt; and IronHacks: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ironhacks.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;www.ironhacks.com&lt;/a&gt;. The program is funded by the Science of Science and Innovation Policy Program (SciSPI) of the National Science Foundation (NSF, Award No. #1462044). Dr. Sabine Brunswicker is the founder and director of RCODI, as well as Associate Professor for Digital Innovation at Purdue University. She also acts as a policy advisor in the USA and Europe and has been a keynote speaker at events like World Economic Forum. no-repeat;center top;;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Austria University Conference 2019 open science and open data, talk Sept 11</title>
      <link>/post/5475-austria-university-conference-2019-open-science-and-open-data-talk-sept-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 00:58:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/5475-austria-university-conference-2019-open-science-and-open-data-talk-sept-11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://rcodi.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/VIENNA.jpg&#34;&gt;https://rcodi.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/VIENNA.jpg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;austria-university-conference-2019-open-science-and-open-data-talk-sept-11&#34;&gt;Austria University Conference 2019 open science and open data, talk Sept 11&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Professor Sabine Brunswicker, Director of RCODI is the Keynote Speaker today at The University Discourse Austria of the Austrian Universities Conference (uniko). Uniko creates space for scientific dialogue on socially relevant topics. Open Science is gaining importance in the scientific community through new ways to collect and share data and research results.  Read more here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://uniko.ac.at/aktuelles/veranstaltungen/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://uniko.ac.at/aktuelles/veranstaltungen/&lt;/a&gt; Link: &lt;a href=&#34;https://uniko.ac.at/aktuelles/veranstaltungen/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://uniko.ac.at/aktuelles/veranstaltungen/&lt;/a&gt; no-repeat;center top;;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IronHacks Fellowship Fall 2018</title>
      <link>/post/5457-fellowship2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Aug 2018 21:44:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/5457-fellowship2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://rcodi.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/CODE-2X1.jpg&#34;&gt;https://rcodi.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/CODE-2X1.jpg&lt;/a&gt; center &lt;img src=&#34;https://rcodi.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/Logo_1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://rcodi.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/Logo_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;rcodi-fellowship-fall-2018&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RCODI Fellowship Fall 2018&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-should-i-become-an-rcodi-undergraduate-fellow-for-fall-2018&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why should I become an RCODI undergraduate fellow for Fall 2018?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our state has a serious workforce problem. There more than 200,000 unfilled jobs and many counties are not taking the right measures to develop the skills of their residents. Do you want to make a change to our state’s workforce problem using data visualization? Become an undergraduate RCODI fellow for Fall 2018 (with a guaranteed stipend for the first 8 weeks) and join a cohort of other 30 to 50 students who want to use their creativity, technical skills, and analytical mind to make an impact on governments!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please review the following steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read the information about the fellowship below.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complete the registration form that is at the end of this page or direct link &lt;a href=&#34;https://rcodi.org/fellowship-registration-form/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;apply-here-httpsrcodiorgfellowship-registration-form&#34;&gt;Apply &lt;a href=&#34;https://rcodi.org/fellowship-registration-form/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-is-the-fellowship-structured&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How is the fellowship structured?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Research Center for Open Digital Innovation (RCODI) is collaborating with the Indiana Department of Workforce Development (DWD) to launch a unique data analytics fellowship program focused on the area of &lt;strong&gt;workforce analytics&lt;/strong&gt;. The fellowship is open for a cohort of undergraduate students enrolled at Purdue University (between 30 to 50 students will be admitted) that go through a two-stage program, including undergraduate research, in which they analyze, visualize and interactively display their results in web-based “app” to be used by policymakers for their decisions on workforce development in the state of Indiana.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The full program is structured in two phases. Phase 1 includes the 8-week program, in which undergraduate students explore open governmental data as well as workforce data available for the selected fellows only (e.g. skill-level, unfilled jobs, training opportunities). They will analyze, visualize the data, and make them actionable in an interactive web “app” using technologies like HTML, CSS, and D3.js (see cool data visualizations done in D3.js in Figure 1 below).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://rcodi.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/Figure1_fellowship.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Figure 1: D3.js visualizations (&lt;a href=&#34;https://d3js.org/&#34;&gt;https://d3js.org/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal is to develop an interactive app that is used by the governmental actors and agencies when making important workforce-related decisions. The first phase is set-up as hacking challenge run by RCODI, in which a cohort of 30 to 50 students go through a structured training and tutorial program, and then participate in 5 iterative hacking events, in which they use their creativity to develop novel and useful workforce apps. Depending on performance in the first 8 weeks, Phase 2 includes the opportunity for a longer-term fellowship follow-on for selected top students to deepen their analysis and advance their project further individually or in a small team setting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first phase lasts 8 weeks and is structured in distinct phases visualized in the figure below. It starts with pre-training sessions to familiarize participants with technologies (e.g. APIs, D3.js) needed, followed by a 5-stage iterative on-campus competition. During this training period, you will also be familiarized with the DWD data during sessions run by representatives of the state, and a team of data scientists. Fellows will have access to tutorials, live help sessions, a social coding environment, and community features. Automatic hosting of apps, code evaluations, and workflow support for usability judging provides additional assistance to the hackers in agile design and prototyping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://rcodi.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/Figure2_fellowship.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Figure 2: Process for phase 1 of the hacking program.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The training period will start on October 12-14th. The competition portion of the fellowship will take place over 5 weekends in October and November (see below). Students will develop their apps in our lab setting on weekends: &lt;strong&gt;October 19-21&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;October 26-28&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;November 2-4&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;November 9-11&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;November 16-18&lt;/strong&gt;. Meeting times on weekends will be defined in coordination with fellows!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-can-the-candidate-gain-from-the-fellowship&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What can the candidate gain from the fellowship?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of the program, the candidates that are chosen to participate will receive a stipend, a certificate of participation, direct interaction with our state’s decisionmakers and other thought leaders in addition to a real working product that can be included in the candidate&amp;rsquo;s digital portfolio for future references. This is on top of the financial “base reward” of $100 for 8 weeks. This base stipend is independent of the performance of the participants. The final financial reward is allocated based on the participants standing in the cohort (below lowest 25% of the participants, better than the lower 25% quartile but worse than 50% of the participants, better than 50% of the fellows but worse than the upper 25%, in the upper 25% quartile). The top 25% can receive a final payment of $800 dollars. The reward depends on how well the fellows score at each stage of the competition in the area of analytics, information visualization, and novelty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-happens-during-the-first-phase-of-the-fellowship&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What happens during the first phase of the fellowship?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You will tackle a real-world challenge in the area of workforce analytics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You will prepare and analyze open data as well as ‘restricted’ data that are exclusively available for the fellows through the collaboration with DWD.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You will advance your skills in HTML, CSS, and D3.js during the training session&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You will use analytical thinking and creativity when exploring, correlating, and visualizing the data in order to respond to the hacking challenge presented to you at the start of the hacking challenge.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You will create and test a web-based app that is novel in terms of data visualization (D3.js) and also interactive features. You will also test your prototype in the lab.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You will participate in and experience experimental lab studies using eye-tracking technologies and data science methods (A/B testing).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You will interact with a team of experts (professors, researchers, representatives of DWD, team members of the chief data scientists of Indiana).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You will have the opportunity to present your final outcomes in a presentation to a board of experts consisting of DWD, other policymakers, and Purdue researchers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your final study will be published as a short whitepaper including a demonstration of your prototype.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sounds overwhelming? We will be here to support you: There are tutors, mentors, etc. who will help you in this program to ramp up fast. We will have a training period! There will be also free food on weekends and drinks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;criteria-for-selection-of-candidates&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Criteria for selection of candidates:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The candidate will need to present proof of the following requirements:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enrolled in a program requiring programming experience (computer science, computer graphics technology, engineering or related areas) or other evidence for prior programming experience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evidence with interest on learning and having experience in developing web applications using HTML/CSS/Javascript&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Problem-solving skills and the ability and willingness to learn new techniques quickly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interest in data visualization and data analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ideally also prior experience with Javascript and D3.js, learning and doing cool stuff!!!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-are-the-next-steps-to-become-part-of-the-fellowship-cohort-for-fall-2018&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are the next steps to become part of the fellowship cohort for Fall 2018?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interested students will need to submit an application &lt;a href=&#34;https://rcodi.org/fellowship-registration-form/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once registration is open, submissions are time sensitive! &lt;strong&gt;The application deadline is Sunday, October 7, 2018 at 11:59pm.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also download the complete information &lt;a href=&#34;https://rcodi.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/Fellowship-document.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;about-rcodi&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About RCODI&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Research Center for Open Digital Innovation (RCODI) at Purdue University brings together an interdisciplinary group of scholars and thinkers focused on the emerging phenomenon of open digital innovation. Open digital innovation encompasses completely new ways we create and use information and data-driven products and services. We design and evaluate data-driven applications and smart technologies to tackle societal challenges such as sustainability, safety, healthy living. Social coding platforms and virtual hacking communities serve as our virtual living labs. Our researchers use advance techniques of computational social science such as behavioral analytics and large-scale online experiments to develop new digital technologies that support humans in the role as citizens, workers, and policymakers in making smarter decisions. As user-inspired researchers, we intensively engage with industry partners, policymakers, and individual citizens. In 2016, RCODI launched Purdue IronHacks, a unique virtual multi-staged open data competition, in which students and innovators develop novel and useful apps to solve societal challenges. More Information about RCODI: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rcodi.org&#34;&gt;www.rcodi.org&lt;/a&gt; and IronHacks: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ironhacks.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;www.ironhacks.com&lt;/a&gt;. The program is funded by the Science of Science and Innovation Policy Program (SciSPI) of the National Science Foundation (NSF, Award No. #1462044). Dr. Sabine Brunswicker is the founder and director of RCODI, as well as Associate Professor for Digital Innovation at Purdue University. She also acts as a policy advisor in the USA and Europe and has been a keynote speaker at events like World Economic Forum. no-repeat;center top;;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RCODI welcomes our new IronHacks fellow Degly Pava from Bogota</title>
      <link>/post/5443-welcome-degly/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 18:33:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/5443-welcome-degly/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://rcodi.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/Degly-Cropped.jpg&#34;&gt;https://rcodi.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/Degly-Cropped.jpg&lt;/a&gt; Welcome to Degly Pava to this semester! He is the winner of Purdue IronHacks - UNAL. Selected candidate from the globalization department and RCODI intern and he will be participating in this next hack as the Community Manager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;I am very pleased to be a Community Manager with RCODI. Thank you again for the opportunity. I am excited to work on such a meaningful project, and I look forward to working in a such a creative environment, working with Dr. Brunswicker and RCODI at Purdue University.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt; no-repeat;center top;;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IronHacks in the News</title>
      <link>/post/5436-ironhacks-on-the-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 03:11:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/5436-ironhacks-on-the-news/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-purdue-research-center-for-open-digital-innovation-honored-four-students-from-the-universidad-nacional-de-colombia-unal-for-their-work-in-the-spring-ironhacks-competition&#34;&gt;The Purdue Research Center for Open Digital Innovation honored four students from the Universidad Nacional de Colombia (UNAL) for their work in the spring IronHacks competition.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;read-more-about-it-herehttpswwwpurdueedunewsroomreleases2018q3appointments-honors-and-activities3html&#34;&gt;Read more about it &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.purdue.edu/newsroom/releases/2018/Q3/appointments,-honors-and-activities3.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;no-repeat;center top;;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RCODI AND INDIANA HOUSING COLLABORATE ON SMART ENERGY PROJECT</title>
      <link>/post/3346-rcodi-and-indiana-housing-collaborate-on-smart-energy-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 00:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/3346-rcodi-and-indiana-housing-collaborate-on-smart-energy-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dr. Brunswicker and her PhD student Marlen Promann are working on a series of perceptual psychological experiments to advance our knowledge of how visual graph structures affect the way we interpret visually represented data. Read more &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.purdue.edu/newsroom/releases/2017/Q4/purdue-faculty,-indiana-housing-pair-up-to-research-energy-use.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
