<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>uncategorized | RCODI</title>
    <link>/category/uncategorized/</link>
      <atom:link href="/category/uncategorized/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>uncategorized</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Purdue Research Center for Open Digital Innovation © 2022</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 01:16:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/media/logo_hue831a1547d228cf33d75a995b069998a_11256_300x300_fit_lanczos_2.png</url>
      <title>uncategorized</title>
      <link>/category/uncategorized/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>RCODI’s Director Co-organizing a Virtual LIVE workshop on Digital Transformation at AOM</title>
      <link>/post/6595-rcodis-director-co-organizing-a-virtual-live-workshop-on-digital-transformation-at-aom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 01:16:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/6595-rcodis-director-co-organizing-a-virtual-live-workshop-on-digital-transformation-at-aom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our director is participating on the 80th annual meeting of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://aom.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Academy of Management&lt;/a&gt;.   What’s new is that this year the meeting is virtual. She will be a co-organizer of a LIVE Professional Development Workshop “What’s New About Digital Transformation? Exploring Interdisciplinary, Multi-Level Research Ideas,” along with five other experts from Switzerland, Italy, Denmark and Germany.  More than 250 have signed up to participate in the virtual workshop so we are eager how this virtual experience on a timely topic will play out!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to our new PhD student at RCODI</title>
      <link>/post/6532-welcome-to-our-new-phd-student-at-rcodi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 18:36:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/6532-welcome-to-our-new-phd-student-at-rcodi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In May 2020, Jia Cheoh was accepted as PhD student of Professor Sabine Brunswicker. Jia will be graduating this semester with a Bachelor’s degree from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cs.purdue.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Department of Computer Science&lt;/a&gt; with a focus in software engineering and notes, “I am excited to get started with this new journey!” She has been supporting the research efforts of Professor Brunswicker over the last few years including the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ironhacks.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;IronHacks&lt;/a&gt; project. Along with her work at RCODI, Jia has experience with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rcac.purdue.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Purdue Supercomputing Center&lt;/a&gt;, Google, and various startups including her own company.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PLOS ONE Call for Papers: Cities as Complex Systems</title>
      <link>/post/6536-plos-one-call-for-papers-cities-as-complex-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 19:25:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/6536-plos-one-call-for-papers-cities-as-complex-systems/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cities are centers of human interactions and the innovations that arise from them. Urbanization has led to many positive developments for society, but also contributes to many of our most pressing challenges, from sustainability and climate change to poverty and inequality. Concepts from complex systems and network theory provide valuable approaches to further our understanding of the processes which drive how cities form, grow, and operate as environments which are more than the sum of their parts. With its commitment to open access, and rigorous, reproducible research,&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://journals.plos.org/plosone/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;is the ideal venue for interdisciplinary complexity science.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Our director, an academic editor of PLOS ONE in the area of network science/complex systems is excited to announce a Call for Papers on Cities as Complex Systems, bringing together researchers across scientific disciplines to build a collection of complex systems and networks research applied to questions in urban science. Our Guest Editors Marta González and Diego Rybski are particularly interested in reading research on urban mobility and energy infrastructures, the morphology and efficiency of cities, and applications to sustainable development goals.&lt;em&gt;Topics may include but are not limited to urban mobility and migration, urban scaling laws, social networks within cities, urban resilience, financial networks within and between cities, smart cities and internet-of-things, and agent-based models of urban phenomena. More details can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://collections.plos.org/s/cities&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;here&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. The submission deadline is July 3, 2020.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New scholar assistants from Colombia arrived to RCODI</title>
      <link>/post/6308-new-scholar-assistants-from-colombia-arrive-to-rcodi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 14:05:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/6308-new-scholar-assistants-from-colombia-arrive-to-rcodi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;new-scholar-assistants-from-colombia-arrived-to-rcodi&#34;&gt;New scholar assistants from Colombia arrived to RCODI&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After running the last version of The Ironhacks contest at Universidad Nacional de Colombia early this year, Cristian Baquero (left on the picture), winner on the Best Solution category, and Alejandro Díaz (left on the picture), Student ambassador of RCODI at Universidad Nacional de Colombia, arrived at Purdue University to assist the Ironhacks Team on research activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both are students of Systems and Computing engineering at Universidad Nacional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the first time Cristian visit the United States; &amp;ldquo;I am very grateful for the opportunity to be here at Purdue, I hope I can learn from Professor Brunswicker a lot and to experience the culture of this country&amp;rdquo; says Cristian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both students will be at campus till January 6th 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Alejandro, this is the second time he came to the States to assist the team as main software developer. He designed and programed the new version of The Ironhacks Platform, a web application that is used to run programing marathons online, which is the main tool used by the team to gather data. &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m here to continue the development process with the team, we aim to run a contest around the world with hundreds of people participating at the same time, this is a very ambitious project!&amp;rdquo; he says.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Student Clerical Job at RCODI Available!</title>
      <link>/post/5892-student-clerical-job-at-rcodi-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 18:51:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/5892-student-clerical-job-at-rcodi-available/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Officially Full Professor - Congratulations to Our Director</title>
      <link>/post/5896-ironhacks-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 23:10:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/5896-ironhacks-2019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://rcodi.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/69C73358-1DD8-42E7-88CB-64EF7012846D.jpg&#34;&gt;https://rcodi.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/69C73358-1DD8-42E7-88CB-64EF7012846D.jpg&lt;/a&gt; UNAL Students pose for a picture at the awards ceremony &lt;a href=&#34;https://rcodi.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/6EEA0899-6AEB-451A-94D5-41DDFD6706C0.jpg&#34;&gt;https://rcodi.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/6EEA0899-6AEB-451A-94D5-41DDFD6706C0.jpg&lt;/a&gt; Ironhacks staff Alejandro Vecchio poses with award winners. The National University of Colombia (UNAL) proved to be a triumphant setting once again for the Research Center for Open Digital Innovation. UNAL students participated in the Spring 2019 Purdue IronHacks competition and were challenged to create an app to help university students find safe and affordable housing in the New York area. For the first treatment group, José Fernando Morantes Florez, Jhonatan Sandoval Velasco, Juan Pulido won first, second, and third respectively; Cristian Adolfo Baquero Pico, Cristian Alejandro Mantilla Duque, and Julián David Rodríguez Ruíz won first second, and third respectively for the second treatment group. With the support from the National Science Foundation and other partners such as Amazon, Red Hat, and the state of Indiana, Purdue IronHacks has undoubtedly made its impact on the global open data movement. no-repeat;center top;; Professor Nicolás Múnera Garzón, a professor at the UNAL whose students participated in Ironhacks, said he was grateful for the opportunity it provided. no-repeat;center top;; “Purdue IronHacks was a great experience for me as a teacher. Students enrolled in the software engineering class with me didn&amp;rsquo;t only learn about the common approach about crafting software that fulfills all technical requirements, they learned also this real need of delivering for real users,” Garzón said. “I&amp;rsquo;m glad and thankful that we worked with incredible people up there at Purdue. The team was always attentive and supporting making the experience even better, so I take this opportunity just to say, thank you! All of you, Alejandro, Sabine, Sebastian&amp;hellip; All of you who were involved with this initiative!” no-repeat;center top;; The IronHacks team has already received emails asking for Ironhacks to continue one more year. no-repeat;center top;; Below, you can find a testimonial video of our winner, Cristian Aldolfo. no-repeat;center top;; About Ironhacks: IronHacks is an 8-week class that combines active learning and app development with a real-world open data competition. It was designed to make hackers familiar with open data released by federal agencies and corporations. Further, it aims to trigger user-centered design of data-driven interfaces with graphs and maps that support end-user decision making. During the 5-stage iterative virtual competition, students utilize open data to create novel and useful online applications (apps) for citizens in areas such as housing, healthcare, etc. Competing participants have access to tutorials, standardized libraries and packages, and virtual help sessions. While they are engaging in an active learning process, their apps are being evaluated using automated techniques and expert judgement. Real time and targeted feedback accelerate their learning process as well as improve their programing skills and their ability to hack complex problems with open data and open standards. no-repeat;center top;; uA19asPOOos 700 400&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhD Candidate Marlen Promann Successfully Defends Dissertation Proposal</title>
      <link>/post/5855-phd-candidate-marlen-promann-successfully-defends-dissertation-proposal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 21:18:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/5855-phd-candidate-marlen-promann-successfully-defends-dissertation-proposal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://rcodi.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/ACM-CHI-2018.jpg&#34;&gt;https://rcodi.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/ACM-CHI-2018.jpg&lt;/a&gt; At the end of last year, on 20th December 2018, Marlen Promann, a Purdue Independent Interdisciplinary PhD candidate (IIGP) , defended her PhD dissertation proposal wherein she asked normative questions about how social data charts support collective awareness and encourage sustainable action in the personal home context. no-repeat;center top;; Promann is interested in the explosive rise of personal data and how they are visualized to end users, nudging them to change their everyday behaviors. Inspired by Elinor Ostrom and her theory of Collective Action, Promann is passionate about leveraging technologies to empower people to collectively manage societal well-fare. Hence,her dissertation explores how charts that depict social data may encourage cooperation around societal issues like recycling, energy conservation, sustainability, social inclusion, etc. that often present users with social dilemmas about doing good in the long term or benefiting oneself in the short term. Ms. Promann uniquely blends her 10+ years of design experience (BA HonsDesign, 2005) and her social scientific research training(MSc Media and Communications, 2010) to integrate perceptual theories of design with social psychological theories to develop theoretical assumptions about how charts may convey the semantics of ‘socialunity’ that may enhance contributions to group goals. Her controlled perceptual experiments confirmed her first hypotheses that particular visual chart structures can indeed enhance perceptions of group unity;however, she found them to have particular semantic meanings of unity (room for more intriguing research). She is now working on a series of behavioral game experiments to see if such perceptual interpretive differences by chart designs can also lead to variable conservation behaviors. no-repeat;center top;; Her dissertation will make three major contributions to three different fields: (1)Pertinent to the Visualization community, Marlen’s findings highlight the importance of encoding data with appropriate visual structures and cues that support rather than contradict the message of the underlying data and/or the goal of the data feedback. (2)Uniquely to the HCI and design communities, Marlen deep dived into the psychological and perceptual theories to inform her chart designs and to empirically measure the causal effects of her designs on the end users. This empirical rigor is what has long been needed to truly test the many novel ideas that emerge within the HCI and design communities. (3)Despite prior efforts to connect the design (HCI) and behavioral science (environmental psychology, smart buildings, energy, etc.), Marlen’s work is at the forefront of connecting theory driven design with empirical evidence of specific visual cues in a design affecting behavior change. (4)Last, but not least, her efforts to leverage behavioral games to test how visual chart design may prime users to cooperate more in social dilemma situations is new to the present games literature that has largely focused on text based feedback. no-repeat;center top;; If you found this interesting, feel free to check out more about the opportunity that positive nudging can have in &lt;a href=&#34;rcodi.org/nudging&#34;&gt;this article.&lt;/a&gt; no-repeat;center top;;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Underrated Questions About Thesis Help</title>
      <link>/post/5612-underrated-questions-about-thesis-help/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2017 22:38:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/5612-underrated-questions-about-thesis-help/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;facts-fiction-and-thesis-help&#34;&gt;Facts, Fiction and Thesis Help&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soon after submitting your purchase, you&amp;rsquo;ll possess the ability to make use of our site to acquire connected with your author and speed that the work. The author&amp;rsquo;s analysis will further his stance around the matter. It is not sufficient to work punctually plus that&amp;rsquo;s the reason why we proofread your work to become sure that it can not include things like misspellings and inaccuracies from the content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They frequently start looking for homework assistance since they do not have enough skills or time to finish their newspaper independently. In many instances, they truly are pleased with the result. In spite of picking the most suitable literature, the college pupils may not need the power to spot the theoretical framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each form of thesis statement performs to strengthen the goal of the certain form of essay writing. It is one of the crucial components of the informative article, as it defines the reach of the essay writing. Writing a thesis statement is most likely being among the most popular senior high school or college assignments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;details-of-thesis-help&#34;&gt;Details of Thesis Help&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you require urgent aid with thesis or dissertation, we could supply you with precisely what you are on the lookout for. Due to plagiarism, the possibility of rejection of thesis are extremely significant. Hence, in the event that you should be prone we to compose a customized fund thesis that&amp;rsquo;s right for you personally then get in touch with us as soon as feasible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At any moment you state that I require advice about my research paper our authors make sure you get the absolute best assistance recalling the ending goal to deliver a great paper to procure you noteworthy tests. Due to years of knowledge and sound subject understanding, they produce quality work and provide you with the ideal. They know what your professors want to get in the newspaper, plus they&amp;rsquo;re going to ensure that each period of one&amp;rsquo;s thesis is written to perfection, so hitting each one the requirements to your very best marks mounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students discover that it&amp;rsquo;s hard to compose a very short and impressive thesis statement and for that reason call for thesis assistance from pros. Because the beginning of the semester, they are inclined to genuinely believe that they have the full time hands for creating their thesis. The pupils want to truly have a high amount of academic adulthood to hunt to find the ideal resources while still writing a thesis proposal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://paramountessays.com/paper-writing-service&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;tick to view&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without proper demo few readers will always be totally hooked up to what you&amp;rsquo;ve composed. Working with experienced master diploma thesis writers will make it quite straightforward to acquire expert work, which will let you surpass each of odds and become the most best. You&amp;rsquo;re going to be provided a completely published paper that&amp;rsquo;s been edited and proofread into this best benchmark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-little-known-secrets-to-thesis-help&#34;&gt;The Little-Known Secrets to Thesis Help&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the event that you would like to compose a tricky and capacious declaration thesis, this can be handy to adhere to a few suggestions and strategies. You may always employ professional thesis writers to locate the task done foryou personally. Fair pricing A expert writer will not charge you quite major prices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever time you say that I require advice about my research paper our authors be certain to make the very most useful assistance recalling the ending objective to give a great newspaper to procure you notable evaluations. They have been familiar with every one of these paths, from the obvious differences, right down to the subtle nuances which make sure they are unique. They truly are reputable and also they really do their very best to add to your educational achievement, you simply need to approach them for help with research paper.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Everybody Is Wrong About Online Assignment</title>
      <link>/post/5636-why-everybody-is-wrong-about-online-assignment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2017 00:55:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/5636-why-everybody-is-wrong-about-online-assignment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-meaning-of-online-assignment&#34;&gt;The Meaning of Online Assignment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The grammar used in writing missions ought to be both accurate and appropriate hence exhaustive understanding of English is going to be more useful. After the initial read, a person needs to prepare yourself to draft a research statement, that is going to be the center of the research paper. Before writing the mission make certain you have known the assignment along with following reading, then you should be aware of the niche area of this difficulties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the event you receive the assignment, make certain you own handouts for the class in order that they understand how to reach you to get more circuit training independently. At precisely exactly the same style, assignments ought to be delivered in time to permit the instructor adequate time to experience the paper. When it did not come into good, his grades would deteriorate appreciably.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;lies-youve-been-told-about-online-assignment&#34;&gt;Lies You&amp;rsquo;ve Been Told About Online Assignment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not just do the top rated internet assignment help providers produce original content, but a variety of them also attach a plagiarism-free report together with the completed assignments at the perfect time of delivery. Finally, the aid of a proof-reader are required. The risk management program ought to be a portion of your general project program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;online-assignment-ideas&#34;&gt;Online Assignment Ideas&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finding your feeble locations and focusing to these is just one of the most useful ways of receiving an assignment help from yourself, family and family members. Our help will be already inside your reach whatever you&amp;rsquo;ve already been delegated. No matter whether it&amp;rsquo;s wrong or right, the truth need to be assessed and concluded in the right way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-good-the-bad-and-online-assignment&#34;&gt;The Good, the Bad and Online Assignment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you receive the assignment, make sure to own handouts for that class so as that they understand just how to reach you for more interval training independently. In order to acquire an assignment support, you could have a communication with the lecturers and investigate in the event of any clarification. Every assignment includes a grade-guarantee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-basics-of-online-assignment&#34;&gt;The Basics of Online Assignment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the 1st scan is completed, make sure that the selected references are correctly marked within one&amp;rsquo;s source sheet. The device of scanning the content enables us omit any sort of mistakes and promises that the completely free plagiarism newspapers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ve got to honestly come up with the caliber of food which you&amp;rsquo;ve experienced at the preferred restaurant. Another more involved way of promote your organization and bring it into a greater profile with the neighborhood community is to give to show photography at no price. The business saw a chance to grow on the web, also began selling throughout the early commercial on-line services, and the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;online-assignment-secrets-that-no-one-else-knows-about&#34;&gt;Online Assignment Secrets That No One Else Knows About&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Constructing a booming debut, you should tell the value of the topic. After the initial read, a person needs to prepare yourself to draft a research statement, that is going to be the center of the research paper. Before writing the assignment create certain you have known the assignment along with following reading, you should be aware of the niche area of the particular difficulties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are able to also sell at Amazon by simply creating your merchandise inside their distinctive format called Kindle Book to become downloadable and readable in their identifying apparatus named the Amazon Kindle Device. Java is a programming information that is more well called a consequence of appropriated nature over web. The software application will take on quite a few files in just about any file format, and may also be set to accept numerous submissions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://papernow.co.uk/essay-writing-service&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;papernow.co.uk/essay-writing-service/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Evidently, among the tastiest advantages it&amp;rsquo;s likely to acquire by calling our aid with your task on the internet is high quality. At exactly the same time, the critical aspects to compare these services would be to assess for the high caliber and pricing they&amp;rsquo;re offering. If you would like to promote a product via your own newsletter, usage of graphics and product images can assist you to get more clients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An individual must do a appropriate market research before settling upon the very most useful kind of service out there. It will be likely to locate a selection of organizations on the internet to assist you with your market research. Now in most regions of Earth, you may utilize online payment process or to sale any sort of product online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;top-online-assignment-secrets&#34;&gt;Top Online Assignment Secrets&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Line-editing might be required. Your boss can use the business&amp;rsquo;s policies to bar you in acquiring a rise. Upon completing the fee payment method, a Confirmation of Receipt goes to be displayed and the EST time stamp is subsequently going to be placed on the entry.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
