<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>open-innovation | RCODI</title>
    <link>/category/open-innovation/</link>
      <atom:link href="/category/open-innovation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>open-innovation</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Purdue Research Center for Open Digital Innovation © 2022</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2010 22:24:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/media/logo_hue831a1547d228cf33d75a995b069998a_11256_300x300_fit_lanczos_2.png</url>
      <title>open-innovation</title>
      <link>/category/open-innovation/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global Open Innovation Executive Study 2014/2015</title>
      <link>/project/2014-2015-global-open-innovation-executive-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2010 22:24:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/2014-2015-global-open-innovation-executive-study/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Open innovation is growing into a mainstream phenomenon of increasing business relevance in large firms where 78 percent of large firms in the sample had been applying open innovation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;global-open-innovation-executive-study&#34;&gt;Global Open Innovation Executive Study&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2012, a large-scale Open Innovation Executive Survey was conducted by UC- Berkeley and Fraunhofer-Society to explore to what extent open innovation was applied in large firms in the USA and Europe. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results show, open innovation is growing into a mainstream phenomenon of increasing business relevance in large firms where 78 percent of large firms in the sample had been applying open innovation, although they were in the early stage of practicing and understanding open innovation. To access the survey report, please click &lt;a href=&#34;http://goo.gl/wC6qRT&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building upon these results, there is a need to advance our understanding of adoption of open innovation at project level. Existing academic literature and theories on open innovation have regularly focused on firm-level aggregates to understand the role of open innovation in firm performance; they have not provided sufficient insights into the adoption of open innovation at a project level. The Research Center for Open Digital Innovation (RCODI) at the Purdue University and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://corporateinnovation.berkeley.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Garwood Center for Corporate Innovation&lt;/a&gt; at the University of California-Berkeley in collaboration with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fraunhofer.de/en.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Fraunhofer-Society&lt;/a&gt; want to address this gap by conducting this research. We implemented the second Open Innovation Executive Survey in order to deepen our understanding of adoption of open innovation not only at firm-level but also at project level. In a nutshell, in this research project, we aim to implement a quantitative survey study on open innovation among senior executives in large firms in the USA, Europe and Japan with the main focus on different open innovation practices, new practices, ways to deal with managing and sharing know-how and IP, and new ways to measure open innovation performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Duration: 22 months (3/2014-1/2016)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;related-research&#34;&gt;Related Research&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing Open Innovation with Business Impact in the Digital Age</title>
      <link>/project/managing-open-innovation-with-business-impact-in-the-digital-age/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2010 22:24:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/managing-open-innovation-with-business-impact-in-the-digital-age/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./acc-logo.png&#34; alt=&#34;featured&#34;&gt;
This study aims to create a guided open innovation framework to help companies leverage optimal value from open innovation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;managing-open-innovation-with-business-impact-in-the-digital-age&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Managing Open Innovation with Business Impact in the Digital Age&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In collaboration with the Accenture Institute for High Performance (AIHP), we have implemented a series of open innovation (OI) case studies to generate new insights on how large, innovative firms use open innovation to solve their strategic innovation problems. One particular example concluded in 2017 is that of Samsung, and its endeavor to seek IoT prototypes created by communities participating in an open innovatoin challenge. Read about it &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.accenture.com/t00010101t000000__w__/gb-en/_acnmedia/pdf-43/accenture-open-innovation-at-samsung.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Dr. Brunswicker and&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the increased digital transformation of many sectors, such problems are increasingly difficult to address. Our preliminary research suggests that one of the keys to running a successful open innovation program is choosing the correct operational mode of open innovation for the business problem at hand. This requires evaluating problem complexity and knowledge uncertainty associated with a business problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A number of companies who have chosen to integrate open innovation have realized that there are specific management practices required to effectively execute open innovation. Open innovation problems can involve a high level of uncertainty and technological complexity and require firms to move from traditional modes of collaboration (such as alliances) towards more open interactions with deeper exchanges of know-how and greater ambiguity such as crowds and communities. There are management challenges specific to open innovation that require a unique set of strategies and processes to be in place in order to overcome these challenges and be able to achieve higher business value through open innovation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study aims to create a guided open innovation framework to help companies leverage optimal value from open innovation by selecting the appropriate open innovation model, and integrating successful management strategies to balance the tensions of knowledge sharing and protection in the midst of strategic and operational ambiguity. This framework will also equip open innovation leaders with new insights into successful practices for creating business impact from open innovation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intellectual Merit and Broader Impacts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Develop a guided open innovation framework to help leverage optimal value.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Proposed successful management strategies to balance the tension between knowledge sharing and protection from the strategic and operational perspective.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Insight into successful practices for creating business impact from open innovation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Investigators:&lt;/strong&gt; Sabine Brunswicker, Mehdi Bagherzadeh&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Partners &amp;amp; Sponsorship&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accenture Institute for High Performance (AIHP)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Governance  and Risk-mitigation of Open Innovation</title>
      <link>/project/governance-and-risk-mitigation-of-open-innovation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2010 22:24:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/governance-and-risk-mitigation-of-open-innovation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This project tests a moderated mediation model in which external search breadth and depth influence open innovation project performance through their effects by different governance mechanisms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;governance-and-risk-mitigation-of-open-innovation&#34;&gt;Governance and Risk-mitigation of Open Innovation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Henry Chesbrough’s (2003) landmark work on open innovation, much attention has been given to the phenomenon of firms’ using a wide range of external actors and sources to help them achieve and sustain innovation (Laursen and Salter, 2006). Prior studies have highlighted the positive influences of open innovation activities on innovation outcomes in large firms (Parida et al., 2012).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, few studies have investigated the key governance mechanism of open innovation and their interaction to induce higher level of innovation performance in specific collaborative open innovation projects. We simultaneously examine the influence of external search breadth and depth in open innovation partners’ interactions on project performance. We contend that: (a) these two dimensions influence open innovation project performance through different governance mechanisms (process control, outcome control); and (b) the project’s related innovation complexity alters the effect of external search breadth and depth on open innovation project performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We develop and test a moderated mediation model in which external search breadth and depth influence open innovation project performance through their effects by different governance mechanisms, and these indirect effects are moderated by different levels of innovation complexity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We applied structural equation modelling (SEM) using the MPlus 7.31 (Muthén &amp;amp; Muthén, 2015) to test for the hypothesized relationships among the constructs: external search breadth and depth, process control, outcome control, innovation complexity and open innovation project performance, as well as for the interaction effects of process control, outcome control and innovation complexity on open innovation project performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intellectual Merit and&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Broader Impacts&lt;/strong&gt;**:**&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Development of a moderated mediation model where the project performance is moderated by the different levels of innovation complexity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
