<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>biology | RCODI</title>
    <link>/category/biology/</link>
      <atom:link href="/category/biology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>biology</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Purdue Research Center for Open Digital Innovation © 2022</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2018 00:51:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/media/logo_hue831a1547d228cf33d75a995b069998a_11256_300x300_fit_lanczos_2.png</url>
      <title>biology</title>
      <link>/category/biology/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding collaboration in open source platforms</title>
      <link>/post/5816-open-source/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2018 00:51:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/5816-open-source/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://rcodi.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/11_3-2X1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt; Everything in life can be connected to a pattern. Whether it be in the way the golden ratio is correlated with growth in shells or how the Pythagorean model is the reason we have stable structures, nature will always hold the key to predicting our own behavior and understanding more about ourselves. It is with this idea that &lt;a href=&#34;https://rcodi.org/ourpeople&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Dr. Sabine Brunswicker and Dr. Satyam Mukherjee&lt;/a&gt; set off to model dynamics between others in design and collaboration. Using the concept of &lt;a href=&#34;https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=313965&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;motif structures&lt;/a&gt;, something typically used for describing and organizing href=&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://science.sciencemag.org/content/298/5594/824%3Ebiological&#34;&gt;http://science.sciencemag.org/content/298/5594/824&amp;gt;biological&lt;/a&gt; systems, the two analyzed how files are linked instead, gaining insight into the collaborative design of source code. left no-repeat;center top;; When reprogramming and re-purposing a certain design part through modifying source files, each individual splits, augments, and inverts which change design interdependence among a small set of files. With this research, we will be able to understand the micro-level design actions that underpin the evolution of a large design artifact developed in fluid organizational forms like open source collaboration. In there, individuals self-select into tasks and make design decisions using simple heuristics (rather than real-option informed design choices). left no-repeat;center top;; Dr. Mukherjee presented their work at the Indian Institute of Management Ahmadabad this month at the international conference on &lt;a href=&#34;http://science.sciencemag.org/content/298/5594/824&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Network Science in Economics and Finance. &lt;/a&gt; left no-repeat;center top;;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
