<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Concluded | RCODI</title>
    <link>/tag/concluded/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/concluded/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Concluded</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Purdue Research Center for Open Digital Innovation © 2022</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2020 18:24:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/media/logo_hue831a1547d228cf33d75a995b069998a_11256_300x300_fit_lanczos_2.png</url>
      <title>Concluded</title>
      <link>/tag/concluded/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Challenge for Social Change</title>
      <link>/project/music-challenge-for-social-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2020 18:24:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/music-challenge-for-social-change/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-tipping-point-community-platform-for-a-x201cmusic-for-social-changex201d-challenge&#34;&gt;The Tipping Point Community Platform for a “Music for Social Change” Challenge&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Powered by RCODI IronHacks&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-do-we-need-it&#34;&gt;Why do we need it?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Science has shown that music can bond people together and motivate them to act collectively. What if during this time of potential ecological and societal collapse, we can use the potential of music to save our future? What if music could trigger &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;social tipping points&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, thresholds at which the actions of a few artists and their fan base engage the masses to act actively in order to realize social change?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And there are young artists who want their art to go beyond “feel good music” and inspire meaningful actions from and with their followers. However, popular metrics such as Billboard Top 100 do not give them sufficient capacity for their songs to become a &lt;strong&gt;Call to Action&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rcodi.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Research Center for Open Digital Innovation  (RCODI)&lt;/a&gt; and its members and fellows, have joined forces with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.earthwisecenter.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;EARTHwise Centre&lt;/a&gt; to change this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OUR VISION:&lt;/strong&gt;  Every artist should have access to a community platform to co-create songs that ignite collective action for a thrivable world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;for-whom-is-it&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For whom is it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our digital platform connects three key actors to co-create a playlist of songs that call a global audience to take action for social change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./globe-black-and-white-world-clip-art-earth-black-and-white.png&#34; alt=&#34;for block on &amp;apos;who uses the platform&amp;apos;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Artists&lt;/strong&gt;
(musicians, cultural creatives) who co-create songs throughout an iterative process&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advisors&lt;/strong&gt;
(experts in “thrivability” focused not only on sustainability but also social and human capital to regenerate planetary, social, cognitive as well as spiritual resources) who advise artists in defining their call for action&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Listeners&lt;/strong&gt;
(you, me, and people around the world) who help artists to learn about the potential of their lyrics and sounds to motivate others to follow their call for action&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-key-features&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The key features&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The community platform offers artists a range of novel features to create songs that ignite action:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OUR SONGS&lt;/strong&gt;: Access to the community’s co-created songs prior to the global release of the tipping point playlist (e.g. via Spotify)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MY STUDIO:&lt;/strong&gt; A space to create and upload different versions of an artist’s song (its audio, its narrative) with features to implement the song’s call for actions (e.g. donations related to the song)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MY RESULTS:&lt;/strong&gt; Access to feedback from advisors and listeners as well as access to song analytics (e.g.
“danceability”, listener engagement)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MY SOCIAL NETWORK&lt;/strong&gt;: Access to a discussion forum to engage in the dialogue with like-minded artists who want to thrive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MY LAB:&lt;/strong&gt; Tools and tutorials to learn about digital music production, “thrivability,” and more&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-benefits-for-artists&#34;&gt;The benefits for artists&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./thrive-spotify.png&#34; alt=&#34;benefits&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Join a community of creatives for social change&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Co-create a song that calls for action&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select a curated global initiatives  (e.g. charity or fund) to implement your song’s call for action&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have your song featured in the Tipping Point channels and playlists&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./bg-pattern-blue-dots.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-research-and-tech-development&#34;&gt;The research and tech development&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our interdisciplinary team of scientists, designers, artists, and platform engineers (more details&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1n-Fgy11di6IUmD8QZKqbZMjFCTDsacnTp8DyCqJSbhc/edit?usp=sharing&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt; here&lt;/a&gt;) can build upon several years of scientific research and practical development experiences on how to design digital platforms for co-creation and collective action. We have worked with thousands of individuals and hackers around the world to scientifically validate platform features, incentive systems, social technologies, and interface designs for co-creation. Such efforts were supported by the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nsf.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;National Science Foundation&lt;/a&gt; and donations from industry leaders who are convinced that digital technologies can democratize innovation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the next few months, we build upon these foundations to design and built the first version of the tipping point community platform. It will use state of the art of web technologies (MERN stack), data science techniques, and AI models (e.g. natural language processing, deep learning, network analytics, agent-based modeling). Our goal is to launch it in summer/fall 2020 along with a global call for the music for social change challenge. This platform will also be the foundation of a multi-year research program focused on the 1) role of music for collective action, 2) the nature of social tipping points in the context of thrivability, and 3) the constituting tole of digital technologies and information design for enabling collective action. You can learn more about the research program &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1n-Fgy11di6IUmD8QZKqbZMjFCTDsacnTp8DyCqJSbhc/edit?usp=sharing&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;our-intended-impact&#34;&gt;Our intended impact&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our goal is that with the launch of a music for social change challenge in fall 2020, we can make impact and:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Involve thousands of artists in the co-creation challenge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create and release a final Spotify playlist with 100 songs calling for collective action across multiple dimensions of social change (e.g. related to different &lt;a href=&#34;https://sustainabledevelopment.un.org/sdgs&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;sustainability development goals&lt;/a&gt; of the United Nations)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Develop new sound and text analytics features (based on machine and deep learning methods) measuring the the latent properties of songs that explains the songs’ potential to enable coherent actions for social change&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use the platform as a “living lab” to understand what features of the platform can &lt;em&gt;unify&lt;/em&gt; the emotions and actions of thousands of people (despite their geographic, cultural, and social differences)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enable and predict social tipping points – thresholds at which songs become viral and motivate the masses to take actions for the social good&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;support-our-vision&#34;&gt;Support our vision&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RCODI and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.earthwise.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;EARTHwise Centre&lt;/a&gt; calls for your support to make this vision reality. Every donation counts so that we can launch the global music for social change challenge soon. Visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.earthwisecentre.org/music-for-change&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;earthwisecentre.org/music-for-change&lt;/a&gt; to support our efforts to use science and music to transform our future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join people around the world and create Your Song of Action. Creating actionable lyrics, melodies, and songs for regenerating Mother Earth and co-creating a world that works for all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.earthwisecentre.org/music-for-change&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;earthwisecentre.org/music-for-change&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global Open Innovation Executive Study 2014/2015</title>
      <link>/project/2014-2015-global-open-innovation-executive-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2010 22:24:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/2014-2015-global-open-innovation-executive-study/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Open innovation is growing into a mainstream phenomenon of increasing business relevance in large firms where 78 percent of large firms in the sample had been applying open innovation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;global-open-innovation-executive-study&#34;&gt;Global Open Innovation Executive Study&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2012, a large-scale Open Innovation Executive Survey was conducted by UC- Berkeley and Fraunhofer-Society to explore to what extent open innovation was applied in large firms in the USA and Europe. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results show, open innovation is growing into a mainstream phenomenon of increasing business relevance in large firms where 78 percent of large firms in the sample had been applying open innovation, although they were in the early stage of practicing and understanding open innovation. To access the survey report, please click &lt;a href=&#34;http://goo.gl/wC6qRT&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building upon these results, there is a need to advance our understanding of adoption of open innovation at project level. Existing academic literature and theories on open innovation have regularly focused on firm-level aggregates to understand the role of open innovation in firm performance; they have not provided sufficient insights into the adoption of open innovation at a project level. The Research Center for Open Digital Innovation (RCODI) at the Purdue University and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://corporateinnovation.berkeley.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Garwood Center for Corporate Innovation&lt;/a&gt; at the University of California-Berkeley in collaboration with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fraunhofer.de/en.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Fraunhofer-Society&lt;/a&gt; want to address this gap by conducting this research. We implemented the second Open Innovation Executive Survey in order to deepen our understanding of adoption of open innovation not only at firm-level but also at project level. In a nutshell, in this research project, we aim to implement a quantitative survey study on open innovation among senior executives in large firms in the USA, Europe and Japan with the main focus on different open innovation practices, new practices, ways to deal with managing and sharing know-how and IP, and new ways to measure open innovation performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Duration: 22 months (3/2014-1/2016)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;related-research&#34;&gt;Related Research&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing Future Megacities with the Crowd: Wicked Urban Problems and Firm-sponsored Civic Innovation Crowdsourcing 2015</title>
      <link>/project/2015-designing-future-megacities-with-crowdsourcing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2010 22:24:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/2015-designing-future-megacities-with-crowdsourcing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This project presents a successful civic innovation crowdsourcing project case study to co-create visionary solutions to the challenge of future mobility in crowded cities around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;designing-future-megacities-with-the-crowd-wicked-urban-problems-and-firm-sponsored-civic-innovation-crowdsourcing-2015&#34;&gt;Designing Future Megacities with the Crowd: Wicked Urban Problems and Firm-sponsored Civic Innovation Crowdsourcing 2015&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the rise of megacities, urban innovators are exposed to increasingly ‘wicked’ societal problems, such as urban mobility. Looking beyond traditional modes for solving these problems, this research sheds light on civic innovation crowdsourcing; a new open model of innovation for solving societal problems in the public and government sector. Through a unique case study, a civic innovation contest sponsored by Bombardier was examined using content analysis. Civic innovation crowdsourcing and how team submissions and geographic contextualization shape the problem solving process was examined in three major cities, Belo Horizonte, Vientiane, and London.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Researchers found that: 1.: Civic Innovation Crowdsourcing creates a diverse set of comprehensive solutions and highlights key complexity attributes from a citizen’s perspective, 2: crowd members tackle complexity at the level of each problem dimension and collectively highlight critical attributes and novel solutions, 3.: Civic Innovation Crowdsourcing furnishes an alternative mode of urban problem solving and affords addressing complexity breadth, and 4.: team and individual submissions differ in the way they address complexity, with teams addressing more attributes of a problem than individuals. This case suggests that designing with the crowd may overcome a central ‘tragedy’ of urban Mobility: While mobility is a greater good that is fundamental for cities to flourish, it puts other public good at risk. Thus, only jointly with the citizens, can businesses, city councils, and NGOs design future mobile urban ecosystems that will ‘evolve’ towards greater economic, social, and ecological performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Investigators: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.time.rwth-aachen.de/cms/TIME/Die-Research-Area/Team/TIM-Team/Externe-Doktoranden/~eepc/Bilgram-Volker/?lidx=1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Volker Bilgram,&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.purdue.edu/opendigital/about/sabine/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Sabine Brunswicker&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uibk.ac.at/smt/innovation-entrepreneurship/team/vita.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Johann Fueller&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keywords:&lt;/strong&gt; Crowdsource; Wicked problems; Civic innovation; Crowdsourcing innovation; Innovation facilitation; Bombardier Inc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Related Publications and News&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brunswicker, S., V. Bilgrim, and J. Fueller. “Taming Wicked Civic Challenges with an Innovation Crowd.” &lt;em&gt;Business Horizons&lt;/em&gt;, 2017. &lt;a href=&#34;https://goo.gl/Y5X5NU&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://goo.gl/Y5X5NU&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Partners:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hyve.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;HYVE AG&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bombardier.com/en/home.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Bombardier&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Increasing Creativity through Anonymous Dissent 2015</title>
      <link>/project/2015-increasing-creativity-through-anonymous-dissent/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2010 22:24:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/2015-increasing-creativity-through-anonymous-dissent/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Working in conjunction with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.brightidea.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Bright Idea&lt;/a&gt;, a leading Open Innovation Platform provider, we are testing the impact of selective anonymity, where participants can flag their contributions to be displayed anonymously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;increasing-creativity-through-anonymous-dissent-2015&#34;&gt;Increasing Creativity through Anonymous Dissent 2015&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Employees within an organization are often encouraged to contribute to internal Open Innovation Challenges, however, the creativity of their contributions may be limited by their perceived freedom to express ideas and opinions that are against majority opinions or organizational norms. Troublesome ideas and opinions may impact their work reputation, standing within the organization, and even their future employment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One option is to make all contributions to internal Open Innovation Challenges anonymous, however, that would reduce the social and reputational rewards associated with participation and co-creation of solutions. Working in conjunction with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.brightidea.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Bright Idea&lt;/a&gt;, a leading Open Innovation Platform provider, we are testing the impact of selective anonymity, where participants can flag their contributions to be displayed anonymously. Using selective anonymity, participants can enjoy all the usual reputational and social rewards that are accrued while participating in an Open Innovation Challenge, while simultaneously offering risk-free minority dissent, which is necessary to increase the diversity of opinions and inspire creativity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are Partnering with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.landcareresearch.co.nz/home&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Landcare Research&lt;/a&gt;, one of seven Crown Research organizations in New Zealand,  to test the effects of selective anonymity on participant contributions. Utilizing a strategic planning question that is of pressing importance to the organization, we will assist Landcare Research by running an internal Open Innovation Challenge on the Bright Idea platform, which includes the opportunity for selective anonymity, and instructions to guide participants in the importance of anonymous contributions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Duration: 6 months (3/2015-8/2015)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Investigators: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.purdue.edu/opendigital/about/sabine/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Sabine Brunswicker&lt;/a&gt;,  &lt;a href=&#34;https://polytechnic.purdue.edu/profile/john1571&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Jeremiah Johnson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Related Publications and News&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Johnson, Jeremiah, Ann Majchrzak, and Sabine Brunswicker. “The Paradox of Minority Dissent in Corporate Innovation Challenges.” Santa Clara, California, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Partners &amp;amp; Sponsorship&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.landcareresearch.co.nz/home&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;[Landcare Research]&lt;/a&gt; New Zealand&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;related-research&#34;&gt;Related Research&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Governance  and Risk-mitigation of Open Innovation</title>
      <link>/project/governance-and-risk-mitigation-of-open-innovation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2010 22:24:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/governance-and-risk-mitigation-of-open-innovation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This project tests a moderated mediation model in which external search breadth and depth influence open innovation project performance through their effects by different governance mechanisms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;governance-and-risk-mitigation-of-open-innovation&#34;&gt;Governance and Risk-mitigation of Open Innovation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Henry Chesbrough’s (2003) landmark work on open innovation, much attention has been given to the phenomenon of firms’ using a wide range of external actors and sources to help them achieve and sustain innovation (Laursen and Salter, 2006). Prior studies have highlighted the positive influences of open innovation activities on innovation outcomes in large firms (Parida et al., 2012).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, few studies have investigated the key governance mechanism of open innovation and their interaction to induce higher level of innovation performance in specific collaborative open innovation projects. We simultaneously examine the influence of external search breadth and depth in open innovation partners’ interactions on project performance. We contend that: (a) these two dimensions influence open innovation project performance through different governance mechanisms (process control, outcome control); and (b) the project’s related innovation complexity alters the effect of external search breadth and depth on open innovation project performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We develop and test a moderated mediation model in which external search breadth and depth influence open innovation project performance through their effects by different governance mechanisms, and these indirect effects are moderated by different levels of innovation complexity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We applied structural equation modelling (SEM) using the MPlus 7.31 (Muthén &amp;amp; Muthén, 2015) to test for the hypothesized relationships among the constructs: external search breadth and depth, process control, outcome control, innovation complexity and open innovation project performance, as well as for the interaction effects of process control, outcome control and innovation complexity on open innovation project performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intellectual Merit and&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Broader Impacts&lt;/strong&gt;**:**&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Development of a moderated mediation model where the project performance is moderated by the different levels of innovation complexity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital practice networks, network dynamics and e-science</title>
      <link>/project/digital-practice-networks-network-dynamics-and-e-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2010 22:23:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/digital-practice-networks-network-dynamics-and-e-science/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This research is aimed at comparing the network effects formed in online digital platforms of participating scientists to “traditional” research and collaboration methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;effect-of-online-digital-communities-to-members-output-success-and-choices-contagion-the-case-nanohub-cyberinfrastructure&#34;&gt;Effect of Online Digital Communities to Members Output (Success) and Choices (Contagion): The Case NanoHUB Cyberinfrastructure&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The primary research questions that sparked this project were: (1) How does scientist output depend upon their embeddedness in digital spaces in NanoHUB.org cyerinfrastructure?; (2) What are the network formation structures and characteristics of an open digital platform?; (3) How do tools traverse (diffuse) amongst users in NanoHUB.org cyberinfrastructure?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using data from the NanoHUB.org cyberinfrastructure analyzed using network science, spatial econometics, and network social modelling techniques, this research is aimed at comparing the network effects formed in online digital platforms of participating scientists to “traditional” research and collaboration methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The formation, mechanism, and process of networks that influence scientists output in digital platforms, like with NanoHUB.org, is limited and contradictory. According to Klimeck et al and nanoHUB.org,  nanoHub.org is a novel science and engineering ecosystem comprised of self-organized researchers, educators, and professionals in eight member institutions that collaborate, share resources, and solve nanotechnology related problems. Results of this project identify the organizational and structural effects of digital platforms to members’ developmental success in addition to diffusion of tools in user community. Also, the network social modelling reveals the network formation patterns and characteristics of online digital platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Duration: 2014 to 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Investigators:  &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.purdue.edu/opendigital/about/sabine/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Sabine Brunswicker&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.agecon.purdue.edu/directory/grad/Munyua.asp&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Philip Munyua&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.krannert.purdue.edu/people/mike-zentner.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Mike Zentner&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://nanohub.org/klimeck&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Gerhard Klimeck&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keywords:&lt;/strong&gt; Digital scientific innovation Scientific, collaboration, Social structure, Programmer communities, Network autocorrelation, Social distance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Related Publications and News&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Related publications: &lt;a href=&#34;http://link.springer.com.ezproxy.lib.purdue.edu/article/10.1007/s11192-016-2106-z&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Creating impact in the digital space: digital practice dependency in communities of digital scientific innovations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brunswicker, Sabine, Sorin Adam Matei, Michael Zentner, Lynn Zentner, and Gerhard Klimeck. “Creating Impact in the Digital Space: Digital Practice Dependency in Communities of Digital Scientific Innovations.” &lt;em&gt;Scientometrics&lt;/em&gt; Online (09 September 2016) (September 9, 2016): 1–26. &lt;a href=&#34;http://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s11192-016-2106-z&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;http://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s11192-016-2106-z&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;partners--sponsorship&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Partners &amp;amp; Sponsorship:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://nanohub.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;NanoHUB.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://nanohub.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Technology Leadership &amp;amp; Innovation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blockchain Networks and Transparency</title>
      <link>/project/blockchain-networks-and-transparency/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2010 00:11:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/blockchain-networks-and-transparency/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This project aims to identify how new ways of constructing exchange are emerging in society&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;blockchain-networks-and-transparency&#34;&gt;Blockchain Networks and Transparency&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intellectual Merit and Broader Impact&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From an interdisciplinary perspective, the research aim is to explore and develop the interlinkage between network science and blockchain technology. One question is how network science can be used to study the blockchain industry and vice versa. This means applying network science concepts and methods to the study and experimental investigation of the blockchain industry. This also includes using blockchain as a technology platform to study the network behavior of the blockchain industry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From an economic perspective, the research aim is to identify how new ways of constructing exchange are emerging in society. The hypothesis to test is that blockchain technology allows a new form of peer-to-peer service provision and exchange between parties, which leads to new conceptualizations, sensibilities, and practices regarding exchange.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From a social perspective, the research program seeks to quantify the amount of intangible social goods produced by the blockchain economy such as freedom, autonomy, dignity, choice, and trust.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Investigators: Melanie Swan, Dr. Sabine Brunswicker&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;related-research&#34;&gt;Related Research&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
