<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>crowdsourcing | RCODI</title>
    <link>/category/crowdsourcing/</link>
      <atom:link href="/category/crowdsourcing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>crowdsourcing</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Purdue Research Center for Open Digital Innovation © 2022</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2010 22:24:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/media/logo_hue831a1547d228cf33d75a995b069998a_11256_300x300_fit_lanczos_2.png</url>
      <title>crowdsourcing</title>
      <link>/category/crowdsourcing/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing Future Megacities with the Crowd: Wicked Urban Problems and Firm-sponsored Civic Innovation Crowdsourcing 2015</title>
      <link>/project/2015-designing-future-megacities-with-crowdsourcing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2010 22:24:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/2015-designing-future-megacities-with-crowdsourcing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This project presents a successful civic innovation crowdsourcing project case study to co-create visionary solutions to the challenge of future mobility in crowded cities around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;designing-future-megacities-with-the-crowd-wicked-urban-problems-and-firm-sponsored-civic-innovation-crowdsourcing-2015&#34;&gt;Designing Future Megacities with the Crowd: Wicked Urban Problems and Firm-sponsored Civic Innovation Crowdsourcing 2015&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the rise of megacities, urban innovators are exposed to increasingly ‘wicked’ societal problems, such as urban mobility. Looking beyond traditional modes for solving these problems, this research sheds light on civic innovation crowdsourcing; a new open model of innovation for solving societal problems in the public and government sector. Through a unique case study, a civic innovation contest sponsored by Bombardier was examined using content analysis. Civic innovation crowdsourcing and how team submissions and geographic contextualization shape the problem solving process was examined in three major cities, Belo Horizonte, Vientiane, and London.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Researchers found that: 1.: Civic Innovation Crowdsourcing creates a diverse set of comprehensive solutions and highlights key complexity attributes from a citizen’s perspective, 2: crowd members tackle complexity at the level of each problem dimension and collectively highlight critical attributes and novel solutions, 3.: Civic Innovation Crowdsourcing furnishes an alternative mode of urban problem solving and affords addressing complexity breadth, and 4.: team and individual submissions differ in the way they address complexity, with teams addressing more attributes of a problem than individuals. This case suggests that designing with the crowd may overcome a central ‘tragedy’ of urban Mobility: While mobility is a greater good that is fundamental for cities to flourish, it puts other public good at risk. Thus, only jointly with the citizens, can businesses, city councils, and NGOs design future mobile urban ecosystems that will ‘evolve’ towards greater economic, social, and ecological performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Investigators: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.time.rwth-aachen.de/cms/TIME/Die-Research-Area/Team/TIM-Team/Externe-Doktoranden/~eepc/Bilgram-Volker/?lidx=1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Volker Bilgram,&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.purdue.edu/opendigital/about/sabine/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Sabine Brunswicker&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uibk.ac.at/smt/innovation-entrepreneurship/team/vita.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Johann Fueller&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keywords:&lt;/strong&gt; Crowdsource; Wicked problems; Civic innovation; Crowdsourcing innovation; Innovation facilitation; Bombardier Inc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Related Publications and News&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brunswicker, S., V. Bilgrim, and J. Fueller. “Taming Wicked Civic Challenges with an Innovation Crowd.” &lt;em&gt;Business Horizons&lt;/em&gt;, 2017. &lt;a href=&#34;https://goo.gl/Y5X5NU&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://goo.gl/Y5X5NU&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Partners:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hyve.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;HYVE AG&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bombardier.com/en/home.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Bombardier&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Increasing Creativity through Anonymous Dissent 2015</title>
      <link>/project/2015-increasing-creativity-through-anonymous-dissent/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2010 22:24:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/2015-increasing-creativity-through-anonymous-dissent/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Working in conjunction with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.brightidea.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Bright Idea&lt;/a&gt;, a leading Open Innovation Platform provider, we are testing the impact of selective anonymity, where participants can flag their contributions to be displayed anonymously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;increasing-creativity-through-anonymous-dissent-2015&#34;&gt;Increasing Creativity through Anonymous Dissent 2015&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Employees within an organization are often encouraged to contribute to internal Open Innovation Challenges, however, the creativity of their contributions may be limited by their perceived freedom to express ideas and opinions that are against majority opinions or organizational norms. Troublesome ideas and opinions may impact their work reputation, standing within the organization, and even their future employment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One option is to make all contributions to internal Open Innovation Challenges anonymous, however, that would reduce the social and reputational rewards associated with participation and co-creation of solutions. Working in conjunction with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.brightidea.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Bright Idea&lt;/a&gt;, a leading Open Innovation Platform provider, we are testing the impact of selective anonymity, where participants can flag their contributions to be displayed anonymously. Using selective anonymity, participants can enjoy all the usual reputational and social rewards that are accrued while participating in an Open Innovation Challenge, while simultaneously offering risk-free minority dissent, which is necessary to increase the diversity of opinions and inspire creativity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are Partnering with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.landcareresearch.co.nz/home&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Landcare Research&lt;/a&gt;, one of seven Crown Research organizations in New Zealand,  to test the effects of selective anonymity on participant contributions. Utilizing a strategic planning question that is of pressing importance to the organization, we will assist Landcare Research by running an internal Open Innovation Challenge on the Bright Idea platform, which includes the opportunity for selective anonymity, and instructions to guide participants in the importance of anonymous contributions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Duration: 6 months (3/2015-8/2015)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Investigators: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.purdue.edu/opendigital/about/sabine/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Sabine Brunswicker&lt;/a&gt;,  &lt;a href=&#34;https://polytechnic.purdue.edu/profile/john1571&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Jeremiah Johnson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Related Publications and News&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Johnson, Jeremiah, Ann Majchrzak, and Sabine Brunswicker. “The Paradox of Minority Dissent in Corporate Innovation Challenges.” Santa Clara, California, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Partners &amp;amp; Sponsorship&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.landcareresearch.co.nz/home&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;[Landcare Research]&lt;/a&gt; New Zealand&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;related-research&#34;&gt;Related Research&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
